We can prepare the body to bring you into fluidic awareness.
水のような意識に入るために、体を準備することができます。
Once the mind disengages.
一度心がそれを断ち切ると。
Because this movement we are about to observe is a movement your body is intimately familiar with.
なぜなら、これから見るこの動きは、あなたの体がよく知っている動きだからです。
You will place your hand, your thumb, your left hand like this.
このように、左手で親指を立てて手を置きます。
We will clench like this.
このように握ります。
You will place it under the axillae.
それを脇の下に置きます。
The axillae.
脇の下。
The left hand and the right hand.
左手と右手。
It faces you; you will use the uppermost finger to place it precisely in the midline
それがあなたの正面に来たら、一番上の指で、それを真ん中に置きます。
at the level of the nasion,
鼻の付け根のあたりに、
you will occlude the right nostril with
右の鼻孔を親指で塞ぎ、
your thumb, you will inhale through the right,
右から息を吸い込みます。
through the left, you inhale, and you inhale, you should already become aware that
左から息を吸い込み、そして息を吸い込むと、あなたはすでに気づいているはずです。
you are inhaling prana,
あなたはプラーナを吸い込むでしょう。
so just become aware that what you have inhaled is your essence.
だから、あなたが吸い込んだものがあなたであるということにただ気づいてください。
of lava, perhaps just a bit of oxygen, but it is also truly an energy, a
溶岩の、おそらく少しの酸素だけですが、それはまた本当にエネルギーであり、光であり、
light, a vibration, an electricity, a pranic energy,
光、振動、電気、エネルギー
you inhale it through
プラーナ的なものを、あなたは吸い込みます。
the left, but very gently, to open the connection towards
左から、しかしゆっくりと、接続を開くために
the sinus, towards the sinus,
副鼻腔へ、副鼻腔へ、
towards your sinuses.
あなたの副鼻腔へ。
Then you occlude the left nostril.
それから左の鼻孔を塞ぎます。
you exhale through the right nostril, then you re-inhale through the right nostril, you
右の鼻孔から息を吐き出し、それから右の鼻孔から再び息を吸い込み、
occlude and you exhale through the left nostril.
動かして、左の鼻孔から息を吐き出します。
And then you continue, you inhale.
そして、あなたは吸い込み続けます。
Try to feel a slight coolness descending towards the
吸い込むときに、副鼻腔に向かって下がる小さな冷たさを感じてみてください。
sinus upon inhalation.
吸い込むときに副鼻腔へ。
Then you stop, you place both hands like this now.
それから止めて、両手をこのように置きます。
You come under the axillae to facilitate optimal opening.
脇の下に手を置いて、よく開きます。
This is a position for the lung.
これは肺のための姿勢です。
This is a position associated with the autumn period.
これは秋の時期の姿勢です。
Now, you will inhale, like this, so deeply.
そこで、あなたは深く息を吸い込みます。
You bring the bolus of air down into the body.
空気の塊を体の中に降ろします。
You exhale through the mouth and you blow out all that is the unnecessary self.
口から息を吐き出し、不要な自己をすべて吹き飛ばします。
All that she sees.
彼女が見るものすべて。
the waste from your body and your thoughts, like this.
あなたの体とあなたの思考の老廃物を、このように。
You re-inhale through the nose.
鼻から再び息を吸い込みます。
And now, we are going to open the central channel.
そして今、私たちは中心のチャネルを開きます。
The channel of your life, you are going to open it a little.
あなたの生命のチャネルを、少し開きます。
For this, you are going to become aware.
そのためには、意識を集中させます。
at the level of the perineum
会陰のレベルで
and you are going to perform a contraction
収縮をします
you are going to perform what is called a Mula Bandha
ムーラバンダと呼ばれるものをします
that means a contraction of the anus and the perineum
それは肛門と会陰の収縮を意味します
you inhale first
まず息を吸い込みます
you contract
収縮させます
the anus and the perineum and you draw up
肛門と会陰を収縮させ、引き上げます
the bolus of air
空気の塊を
and the diaphragm while performing a Mula Bandha
そしてムーラバンダをしながら横隔膜を
and you draw everything up to the crown of the head
そして頭のてっぺんまで全てを引き上げます
you tuck the chin, you close the glottis
顎を引き、声門を閉じます
and you try to bring this into your central channel
そしてそれをあなたの中心管に持っていこうとします
and you exhale
そして息を吐きます
and you push, you push the prana that must ascend from
そして、あなたはプラーナを押し上げます。それはそこから上昇しなければなりません。
from there, you inhale, you close
そこから、息を吸い込み、閉じます
the perineum, the anus, you draw up by pushing the
会陰、肛門を締め、押し上げながら
bolus upwards, becoming aware
空気の塊を上に押し上げ、意識しながら
of the crown of your head, you tuck the chin, you close the glottis.
頭のてっぺんを意識し、顎を引き、声門を閉じます。
One last time, you inhale, then
もう一度、息を吸い込み、それから
you exhale the air, do like this, first
息を吐き出します。このように、まず
take a deep, ample breath, then exhale completely, and you
大きく、たくさんの息を吸い込み、吐き出し、
hold,
止めます。
You elevate the diaphragm, and you visualize its movement.
横隔膜を引き上げ、それを描きます。
You release.
緩めます。
This action gently engages the musculature, inducing a subtle warming sensation throughout the body.
これで少し筋肉が活性化され、体が少し温まります。
Then, position yourself in an upright, stable seated posture.
そして、まっすぐ座ります。
Within the corporeal form, you
体の中で、あなたは
gently settle yourself here, establishing a profound connection with the physical body,
このようにゆっくりと、体としっかりと接触します
physical body, ensuring a stable grounding with the earth, you
肉体としっかりと接触し、大地としっかりと接触し、
conceptualize a triangular form, as if sketching a mountain, with
三角形のように、まるで山を描くように、
its four facets.
四つの面を持つ山のように。
you position yourself, you settle within your mountain, you possess a
あなたは自分の山の中に座り、
solid foundation, observe,
良い基盤を持っています。
we possess an apex,
頂上があります。
and ultimately, the emotional climate of our existence manifests,
そして最終的に、私たちの人生には感情的な天候があります。
we acknowledge the transient nature of all phenomena,
全てが過ぎ去ることを知っています。
the mountain consistently maintains an immutable state.
山は常に不変の段階にあります。
While storms and various disturbances may arise, there exists an intrinsic part of
嵐が来たり、色々なことがあったりしても、あなたの中には決して触れられない部分があります。
yourself, and you gradually endeavor to access this intrinsic aspect of your being that is never
あなたの中には、決して触れられない部分があります。
affected.
決して触れられない部分があります。
It is akin to an inherent component of the
それはあなたの
essence of your consciousness. Immerse yourself within this essence.
精神の性質の一部です。あなたはその性質の中に身を置きます。
Each individual possesses a vital center. Humanity
私たち一人ひとりに重要な中心があります。人間は
can subsist without conscious awareness of possessing this center.
この中心を持っていることを知らずに生きることができます。
However, one cannot exist without the inherent presence of this center; you
しかし、この中心が存在しなければ生きることはできません。あなたは
can live
生きることができます。
without knowing you possess this center, yet you cannot live without this center.
この中心を持っていることを知らずに生きることはできますが、この中心なしでは生きることはできません。
Each of us is endowed with a center, yet not necessarily with the conscious knowledge of
私たち一人ひとりは、中心を持っていますが、その中心の
this center.
知識は持っていません。
And this knowledge...
そして、この知識は...
It must be acquired; it must be experienced.
それを習得し、経験する必要があります。
It is primarily about becoming aware of your connection to the universe.
まず、あなたが宇宙とつながっていることを意識することです。
For a moment, endeavor to realize that you are an integral part of this
一瞬、あなたがこの
unity.
一体の一部であることを認識してみてください。
Each one of you...
あなた方一人ひとりが...
Be part of this
この
species, of this universe.
種、この宇宙の一部です。
We are all interdependent.
私たちは皆、相互依存しています。
One must comprehend interdependence.
相互依存を理解する必要があります。
If you grasp interdependence, you ultimately comprehend the
相互依存を理解すれば、最終的に
sense of responsibility.
責任の意味を理解できます。
And to become cognizant of your roots, recognizing that we are not
そして、自分のルーツを意識すること、私たちは
alone, but rather that we constitute
一人ではなく、
part of a greater whole.
全体の一部であるということです。
Once this understanding is achieved, you can rediscover a state of intrinsic harmony.
それを理解すれば、自分の中に一種の調和を見出すことができます。
This harmony must be re-established beyond conceptual boundaries.
この調和は、概念的な境界を超えて見出されるべきです。
a crucial center
重要な中心
which is truly the initial discovery
最初に本当に発見すべきは
it is to return to the abdomen
お腹に戻ることです
thus
だから
like an infant
子供のように
when you observe an infant
子供を見ると
when you observe a baby
赤ちゃんを見ると
you observe that the infant
子供が
is at the core
中心にいるのがわかります
of the human being, as it resides within its abdomen. It respires with its
人間のお腹の中にいるからです。お腹で呼吸し、
abdomen. It vitalizes through its
お腹で生きています。
abdomen. It does not vitalize through its head, nor through its heart,
頭や心臓ではなく、お腹で生きています。
but very rapidly, it will deviate
しかし、すぐに彼は
from this vital core. You position yourself, you
この生命の中心から離れていきます。あなたは、あなたは
Become aware of the abdomen.
お腹を意識してください。
You breathe for a moment.
あなたはしばらく呼吸します。
Each time you inhale, the universe exhales.
息を吸うたびに、宇宙は息を吐きます。
Each time you exhale, the universe inhales.
息を吐くたびに、宇宙は息を吸います。
Try to return to this center; if you are in this center, it is
この中心に戻ろうとしてください。もしあなたがこの中心にいるなら、それは
the beginning, it is returning
始まりです、それは戻ることです
first to the entrance of your home, afterwards
まずあなたの家の玄関に、その後
you will go into the heart.
あなたは心臓に行くでしょう。
Then you will go into the head
それからあなたは頭に行くでしょう
You will learn love
あなたは愛を学ぶでしょう
You will learn to be loved
あなたは愛されることを学ぶでしょう
Then you will realize that you are happy when you are there
それからあなたはそこにいるとき幸せだと気づくでしょう
Always remain connected to this center
常にこの中心とつながり続けてください
And then we will simply do
そして、私たちはただ行うだけです
a few conscious breaths with the abdomen.
お腹を使ったいくつかの意識的な呼吸。
You will become aware of the navel, not
あなたはへそを意識するでしょう、しかし
as an egoistic center, but as
利己的な中心としてではなく、
So, a connection with the universe here.
だから、ここで宇宙とのつながり。
There you go.
はい。
You maintain this connection today, like this.
あなたは今日、このつながりをこのように保ちます。
You remain centered here.
あなたはここで集中し続けます。
Afterwards, we will work on other levels.
その後、私たちは他のレベルで作業します。
It is a basic connection, a fundamental connection on a vital plane.
これは基本的なつながりであり、生命の平面上の基本的なつながりです。
And we will see that the brain, in this development that we will observe today,
そして、今日見るこの発達において、脳が
will be dependent on this vitality.
この生命力に依存することになるのを見るでしょう。
It will need this energy, it
それはこのエネルギーを必要とし、
will need the heart to develop.
発達するために心臓を必要とするでしょう。
What will happen here will happen there.
ここで起こることは、あそこで起こるでしょう。
There are currents.
流れがあります。
both fluidic, which is important,
流動的であり、それは重要です、
mesenteric, splenic,
腸間膜、脾臓、
or we can say vitelline or umbilical,
または卵黄嚢または臍帯と言うこともできます、
which will integrate into the heart,
それらは心臓に統合され、
which will redistribute this
それはそれを再分配します
via the carotid system
頸動脈系を介して
or the vertebral system,
または椎骨系、
that is, through four major pathways,
つまり、4つの主要な経路によって、
to return towards the basilar trunk
脳底動脈に戻り、
and distribute it to the heart, the brain.
それを心臓、脳に分配します。
So with each pulsation,
だから、拍動ごとに、
we find the pulsation in the brain.
脳にも拍動が見られます。
Thus the heart,
つまり、心臓、
the brain and the brain,
脳、そして脳、
heart and
心臓、そして
the intestine are completely
腸は完全に
in functional unity. I cannot separate them.
機能的な統一性を持っています。それらを分離することはできません。
Even in your practice,
あなたの施術においても、
if you perform work
もし頭蓋の施術をするなら、
on a cranial plane,
今日一緒にそれを見直しますが、
you will see, we will review this together today,
それを認識してもらうことが目的です。
but it is to make you perceive this.
最終的に、
That ultimately,
これらの構造の
the profound development
深い発達は、
of these structures will be
この相互依存に依存するでしょう。
dependent on this interdependence.
それが、
So this is it.
本当に理解すべき重要な点です。相互依存の概念です。
This is what is truly important to understand: the concept of interdependence.
だから、頭蓋の施術をするとき、私は頭蓋だけを施術しているのではありません。
That's why when I do cranial work, I'm not just doing cranial work.
内臓の施術をするとき、私は内臓だけを施術しているのではありません。
When I do visceral work, I'm not just doing visceral work.
私はオステオパシーを施術しています。
I am practicing osteopathy.
私は頭蓋の施術をすることはめったにありません。
In these fluidic conditions, I very rarely engage in cranial treatment, very rarely.
私はそれをその腹部に戻し、その腹部で再調整します。
I return it to its primary field, I re-establish its balance within its primary field,
そして残りのすべての力は空気中にあります。
and the full potency is then allowed to express itself.
その後、少し方向付けが必要かもしれません。
Subsequently, some guidance may be required.
頭蓋がどのように発達するかを理解する。この2日間で、私たちは
to comprehend the developmental process of the cranium. Therefore, over these two days, we will examine
胚レベルで頭蓋がどのように発達するかを研究し、そして私たちはそれを見るでしょう...
the embryological development of the cranium, and we will observe that...
頭蓋がどのように発達するかを研究し、そして私たちはそれを見るでしょう...